JAKE: When I was lying there
in the VA hospital,
with a big hole blown
through the middle of my life,
I started having
these dreams of flying.
I was free.
Sooner or later, though,
you always have to wake up.
(SIGHS)
(MONITOR BEEPING)
In cryo, you don't
dream at all.
It doesn't feel
like six years.
More like a fifth of tequila
and an ass-kicking.
Tommy was the scientist, not me.
He was the one who wanted to
get shot light-years out in space
to find the answers.
Are we there yet?
Yeah, we're there, sunshine.
We're there.
AGENT 1: It's about your brother.
JAKE: So, a week before Tommy's gonna
ship out, a guy with a gun ends his journey
for the paper in his wallet.
You've been in cryo for five years,
nine months and 22 days.
You will be hungry. You will be weak.
If you feel nausea, please use the sacks...
JAKE: Yeah, Tommy was the scientist.
Me, I'm just another dumb grunt
going some place he's gonna regret.
Up ahead was Pandora.
You grew up hearing about it, but
I never figured I'd be going there.
Your brother represented
a significant investment.
We'd like to talk to you
about taking over his contract.
And since your genome is identical
to his, you could step into his shoes,
so to speak.
AGENT 1: It'd be a fresh start
on a new world.
AGENT 2: And the pay is good.
Very good.
-Exo-packs on! Let's go! Exo-packs on!
-ASSISTANT: Exo-packs on! Let's go!
Remember, people,
you lose that mask,
you're unconscious in 20 seconds,
you're dead in four minutes!
Let's nobody be dead today!
Looks very bad on my report.
Hell's Gate tower, this
is TAV 1-6 on approach.
Crossing outer marker.
Mine is in sight.
JAKE: One life ends,
another begins.
Harnesses off!
Get your packs!
-Put it together, let's go! Let's go!
-ASSISTANT: Harnesses off! One minute!
When that ramp comes down,
go directly into the base. Do not stop!
Go straight inside.
Wait for my mark!
Go, go, go, go! Get out of there!
Keep moving! Let's go, let's go!
JAKE: There's no such thing
as an ex-Marine.
You may be out, but you
never lose the attitude.
I told myself I could pass
any test a man could pass.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
They can fix a spinal,
if you got the money,
but not on vet benefits,
not in this economy.
Let's go, special case!
Do not make me wait for you!
Well, well, ladies.
Look at all this fresh meat! Whoo!
JAKE: Back on Earth, these guys
were Army dogs, Marines,
fighting for freedom.
AMPSUIT OPERATOR: Look out, hot rod!
JAKE: But out here
they're just hired guns,
taking the money,
working for the company.
Check this out, man.
Meals on wheels.
Oh, man, that is just wrong.
MAN 1 : I got two guys free
in about 20 minutes!
MAN 2: Got it! Need them!
QUARITCH: You're not in Kansas anymore.
You are on Pandora,
ladies and gentlemen.
Respect that fact
every second of every day.
If there is a hell,
you might want to go there for
some R&R after a tour on Pandora.
Out there,
beyond that fence,
every living thing that crawls,
flies or squats in the mud
wants to kill you and
eat your eyes for Jujubes.
We have an indigenous population
of humanoids called the Na'vi.
They're fond of arrows
dipped in a neurotoxin
that'll stop your heart
in one minute.
And they have bones reinforced
with naturally occurring carbon fiber.
They are very hard to kill.
As head of security,
it is my job to keep you alive.
I will not succeed.
Not with all of you.
If you wish to survive,
you need to cultivate
a strong mental attitude.
You've got to obey the rules.
Pandora rules.
Rule number one...
JAKE: There's nothing like an old-school
safety brief to put your mind at ease.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Jake!
You're Jake, right?
Tom's brother.
Wow! You look just like him.
Sorry, I'm Norm. Spellman. I went
through avatar training with him.
(CHUCKLING)
...into the bio-lab.
We're gonna spend
a lot of time up here.
Hey! How you doing?
Norm, avatar driver.
FEMALE SCIENTIST: Hi.
MALE SCIENTIST: Hey.
Link... Here's the link room right here. This
is where we're connecting to the avatar.
JAKE: Me and Norm are here to drive these
remotely controlled bodies called avatars.
And they're grown from human DNA
mixed with the DNA of the natives.
-Hey. Welcome.
-Hey.
-Welcome to Pandora. Good to have you.
-Thanks.
(LAUGHS) Damn! They got big.
Yeah, they fully mature
on the flight out.
So the proprioceptive sims
seem to work really well.
Yeah, they've got
great muscle tone.
It'll take us a few hours
to get them decanted,
but you guys can take
them out tomorrow.
There's yours.
Hey. Dr. Norm Spellman.
-Dr. Max Patel. Great to meet you.
-NORM: Good to meet you, yeah.
(HEARTBEAT THUMPING)
Looks like him.
No, it looks like you.
NORM: This is your
avatar now, Jake.
JAKE: And the concept is that every driver
is matched to his own avatar,
so that their nervous
systems are in tune,
or something.
Which is why they offered me the gig,
because I can link with Tommy's avatar,
which is insanely expensive.
Is this right? I just say
whatever to the video log?
Yeah, we gotta get in the habit
of documenting everything.
You know, what we see, what
we feel. It's all part of the science.
And good science
is good observation.
Plus it'll help to keep you
sane for the next six years.
All right. Whatever.
So...
Well, here I am,
doing science.
MALE TECHNICIAN: They're coming out!
WOMAN ON PA: Attention.
Drivers coming out of link.
(SIGHING) Oh, God.
(GROANS)
FEMALE TECH: Where's the lab coat?
Where's the lab coat?
Who's got my
goddamn cigarette?
Guys!
What's wrong with this picture?
Thank you!
NORM: Grace Augustine
is a legend.
She's the head of the Avatar
Program. She wrote the book,
I mean, literally wrote the
book on Pandoran botany.
Well, that's 'cause she likes
plants better than people.
Here she is, Cinderella
back from the ball.
Grace, I'd like you to
meet Norm Spellman
and Jake Sully.
Norm. I hear good things
about you. How's your Na'vi?
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
May the All Mother...
...smile upon our first meeting.
Not bad.
You sound a little formal.
(CHUCKLES)
I studies for five years...
...but there is much to learn.
Grace? This
is Jake Sully.
Ma'am.
Yeah, yeah. I know who you are,
and I don't need you.
I need your brother.
You know, the PhD who trained
for three years for this mission?
He's dead. I know it's a big
inconvenience for everyone.
How much lab training have you had?
I dissected a frog once.
You see?
You see? I mean,
they're just pissing on us
without even the courtesy
of calling it rain.
-I'm going to Selfridge.
-No, Grace,
-I don't think that's a good idea.
-No, man, this is such bullshit!
I'm gonna kick
his corporate butt.
He has no business sticking
his nose in my department.
Here tomorrow, 0800.
Try and use big words.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING ON RADIO)
Scorpion Two-Hotel, Hell's Gate tower.
You are cleared for south departure.
Hover taxi, Delta
runway. Squawk ident.
-Mmm! You see that?
-Yes, sir.
No, you didn't. You were
looking at the monitor.
I love this putter, Ronnie!
I love this putter.
Parker, you know, I used to
think it was benign neglect,
but now I see that you're
intentionally screwing me.
Grace, you know,
I enjoy our little talks.
Oops.
I need a researcher.
Not some jarhead dropout.
Well, actually, I thought
we got lucky with him.
-Lucky?
-Yeah.
How is this in any way lucky?
Lucky your guy
had a twin brother,
and lucky that brother wasn't
some oral hygienist or something.
A Marine we can use. I'm assigning
him to your team as security escort.
The last thing I need is another
trigger-happy moron out there!
Look, look, you're supposed to be winning
the hearts and the minds of the natives.
Isn't that the whole point
of your little puppet show?
If you look like them and you talk
like them, then they'll start trusting us.
We build them a school,
we teach them English,
but after, what, how many years?
Relations with the indigenous
are only getting worse.
Yeah, that tends to happen when
you use machine guns on them.
Right. Come here.
I can't...
This is why we're
here. Unobtanium.
Because this little gray rock
sells for 20 million a kilo.
That's the only reason. It's
what pays for the whole party.
It's what pays for your science.
Comprendo?
Now, those savages are
threatening our whole operation,
we're on the brink of war,
and you're supposed to be
finding a diplomatic solution.
So use what you've got,
and get me some results.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
-So, how much link time have you logged?
-About 520 hours.
That's good.
You're in there.
-You're here. How much have you logged?
-Zip.
But I read a manual.
Tell me you're joking.
This is cool.
Let's go.
Don't.
I got this.
(SIGHING) So you just figured
you'd come out here,
to the most hostile
environment known to man,
with no training of any kind,
and see how it went?
What was going through your head?
Maybe I was sick of doctors
telling me what I couldn't do.
-Biometrics are good.
-Link three is ready.
Keep your arms in, hands in,
head down.
Down. Just relax and
let your mind go blank.
That shouldn't
be hard for you.
(CHUCKLING) Kiss the
darkest part of my lily white...
Initiate link.
Run sequence
unit three. Go.
LINK TECH: Launching.
I have the first congruency.
That's a gorgeous
brain. Nice activity.
Hmm. Go figure.
Phase-lock 40%.
All right. Going in.
I'm going in in four.
Phase-lock 99%.
Link is stable.
(RESPIRATOR HISSING)
(DISTANTLY) He's in.
Jake, can you hear me?
Can you hear me, Jake?
Pupillary reflex
is good.
Pinna response normal.
How you feeling, Jake?
Hey, guys.
(CHUCKLES) Welcome to your
new body, Jake.
FEMALE TECH: Good!
Yeah, we're gonna take this
nice and easy, Jake.
-And touch your thumb to your fingers.
-Yeah.
-Thumb to your fingers.
-No problem.
That's good. I can see
you can remember that one.
-Got it.
-Well, if you want to sit up,
-that's fine.
-Okay, good. Just take it
nice and slow, Jake. Good. Okay,
well, no truncal ataxia, that's good.
Are you feeling lightheaded
or dizzy at all?
You're wiggling your toes!
-MALE TECH: Good. Good, Jake.
-That's great.
(JAKE GASPING IN AMAZEMENT)
Distal motor control is good. Good, Jake.
Are you feeling any numbness or pain?
-That's great, Jake. Hold on, now.
-FEMALE TECH: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Take it easy. Don't get
ahead of yourself, okay?
There's a few more sensory
motor reflex tests we need to run,
-so take it easy.
-Ooh! Wait.
-Jake.
-Sit down, Jake.
Jake! Listen to me.
-Whoa.
-Jake!
-I need you to sit down. Jake!
-It's okay.
-Buddy, listen to me.
-It's all good. I got this.
Jake, you need to
sit down right now.
Guys, get him back
on the gurney now.
Listen to me. For your own
safety, you need to sit down.
You need time to adjust to
the avatar... Whoa! Jake!
-God, Jake, watch your tail.
-(LAUGHING) Yeah!
Sedate! Sedate him! A thousand
milligrams of Supitocam! Stat!
MAX: Guys! Guys!
Whoa! Whoa!
NORM ON INTERCOM: By the numbers.
-Jake. Come on.
-Jake! Listen to me.
You're not used to
your avatar body.
-This is dangerous.
-This is great.
-MAX: Jake? Jake, listen to me.
-Come on. They're gonna put you out.
(JAKE LAUGHING)
-MALE TECH: Norm, sit down.
-No, no. I gotta get out of these leads.
God damn it! Bring them home!
-Norm! Do not leave control!
-FEMALE TECH: You're not ready for it!
-Oh, come on, you ain't got no skills.
-Ooh! Ooh! So close!
I don't even have to
play defense on it.
-Hey, guys. Hey.
-MALE AVATAR: Whoa.
NORM: It's okay,
I'll get him.
Jake, you have to come back!
Jake! Jake! Excuse me.
-Watch it!
-Sorry!
Come on!
Jake! We're not
supposed to be running!
(LAUGHING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING) Jeez! Sorry.
Watch it!
GRACE: Hey, Marine!
Damn.
-Grace?
-Well, who'd you expect, numbnuts?
Think fast.
Motor control's looking good.
(CHUCKLING APPRECIATIVELY)
(CHUCKLES)
GRACE: Come on, everybody, quiet down!
All right, gang,
lights out.
Come on, Louise, chop-chop.
Hey, hey, hey!
GRACE: Don't play with that,
you'll go blind.
That's kind of freaky.
Come on. Scat.
Good night.
Lights out! See you
at dinner, kiddies.
(CREATURES SCREECHING)
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
MAX: Welcome back.
You okay? You all right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I'm Trudy.
I fly all the science sorties.
And this here is my baby.
Hold on a second.
Hey, Wainfleet! Get it done!
-We bounce at zero-nine.
-Yeah, I'm on it, capitaine!
Vine strike's still loose.
You guys are packing some heavy gear.
Watch it!
Yeah, that's 'cause we're not the
only thing flying around out there.
Or the biggest.
I'm gonna need you on a
door gun. I'm a man short.
I thought you'd never ask.
There's your man.
See you on the flight line.
You wanted to see me, Colonel?
This low gravity'll
make you soft.
You get soft,
Pandora will shit you out
dead with zero warning.
I pulled your record, Corporal.
Venezuela, that was some mean bush.
Nothing like this here, though.
You got some heart, kid,
showing up in this neighborhood.
I figured it's just
another hellhole.
I was First Recon myself.
A few years ahead of you.
Well, maybe more than a few.
Three tours Nigeria,
not a scratch.
I come out here?
Day one. Think I felt
like a shavetail louie?
Yeah. Oh, they could fix
me up, if I rotated back.
Yeah, and make me pretty again.
But you know what?
I kind of like it.
It reminds me every day
what's waiting out there.
Hup! The Avatar Program
is a bad joke.
Bunch of limp-dick
science majors.
However, it does present an opportunity
both timely and unique.
-Clear!
-MAN: Clear!
(POWERING UP)
A recon gyrene in an avatar
body. That's a potent mix.
Give me the goose bumps.
Such a Marine
could provide the intel I need,
right on the ground.
Right in the hostiles' camp.
Look, Sully. I want you
to learn these savages from the inside.
I want you to gain their trust.
I need to know how to
force their cooperation
or hammer them
hard if they won't.
-Am I still with Augustine?
-On paper.
Yeah, you walk like one of her
science pukes, you quack like one,
but you report to me.
Can you do that for me, son?
Hell, yeah, sir.
Well, all right, then.
Son, I take care of my own.
You get me what I need, I'll see to it you
get your legs back when you rotate home.
Your real legs.
That sounds real good, sir.
-Link's ready!
-LINK TECH: Phase-lock 40%.
Just keep your mouth shut
and let Norm do the talking.
LINK TECH: I have five congruencies.
Phase-lock 90%.
MAX: Link three ready.
GRACE: All right, I'm going in.
(SQUAWKING)
(WHOOPING)
(CHUCKLING)
Shut it down. We're
gonna stay a while.
-Norm! Your pack.
-Pack.
Stay with the ship.
One idiot with a gun is enough.
You the man, Doc.
(DISTANT YOWLING)
(CREATURE COOING)
(SQUEAKING)
GRACE: Prolemuris.
They're not aggressive.
Relax, Marine. You're
making me nervous.
NORM: So, how will they
know we're here?
GRACE: I'm sure they're
watching us right now.
JAKE: Keep moving, Norm.
GRACE: Keep up, guys!
GRACE: And here I go.
NORM: Scanning.
Oh, wow! It's that fast?
-(LAUGHING) Amazing, isn't it?
-Yeah.
So, that is signal transduction
from this root
to the root of the tree next to it.
So, we should take a sample.
NORM: Okay. Sample.
NORM: You know, it's probably electrical,
based on the speed of the reaction.
GRACE: Norm, you've contaminated
the sample with your saliva.
NORM: Right.
(GASPS)
GRACE: So, here I go.
(GRACE CONTINUES CHATTERING)
(LAUGHING)
(TRUMPETING)
Don't shoot.
Don't shoot,
you'll piss him off.
(TRUMPETING)
It's already pissed off.
Jake, that armor's
too thick. Trust me.
It's a territorial threat display.
Do not run,
or he'll charge.
So, what do I do, dance with it?
Just hold your ground.
(GROWLING)
(TRUMPETING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
Yeah? Come on!
What you got?
Oh, yeah. Who's
bad? That's right.
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about, bitch.
That's right, get your
punk ass back to mommy.
Yeah? Yeah, you got nothing.
You keep running.
Yeah, and why don't you bring
back some of your friends, huh?
(SNARLING SOFTLY)
(ROARING)
Oh, shit.
(CREATURES ROARING)
So what about this one?
Run? Don't run? What?
Run! Definitely run!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
I'm gonna have to call it, guys. We're not
allowed to run night ops. Colonel's orders.
I'm sorry, Doc,
he's just gonna have to
hang on till morning.
He won't make it till morning.
(CREATURES CHITTERING)
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(CREATURES GROWLING)
(CREATURES HISSING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(CHITTERING)
(SNARLING)
(SNARLS)
(HISSING)
I don't have all goddamn night.
Come on! Come on!
(YELPS)
(YELPING)
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(YELPS)
(YELLING)
(YELPING)
(GRUNTING)
(HISSING)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
JAKE: Hey, wait. Don't!
(SCOFFS)
Great.
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
(WHIMPERING STOPS)
Look, I know you probably
don't understand this,
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
But thank you.
Thank you.
That was pretty impressive.
I would have been screwed if
you hadn't come along. It was...
Hey, wait a second.
Hey, where you going?
Wait up!
Just... Hey, slow down.
Look, wait up, I just wanted to say
thanks for killing those things.
(EXCLAIMS IN PAIN)
Damn!
Don't thank.
You don't thank for this.
This is sad.
Very sad only.
Okay. Okay. I'm sorry.
Whatever I did,
I am sorry.
All this is your fault.
They did not need to die.
My fault? They attacked me.
How am I the bad guy?
-Your fault!
-Whoa!
-(GENTLY) Shh. Easy. Easy.
You're like a baby. Making noise,
don't know what to do.
Easy. Shh.
Fine.
If you love your
little forest friends,
why not let them
just kill my ass?
What's the thinking?
Why save you?
Yeah. Yeah, why save me?
You have a strong heart.
No fear.
But stupid!
Ignorant like a child.
(SCOFFS)
Well, if I'm like
a child, then...
Look, maybe you should teach me.
Sky People cannot learn.
You do not See.
Well, then teach me how to See.
-No one can teach you to See.
-Whoa.
Look, come on,
can't we talk?
Say, where'd you learn to speak
English? Dr. Augustine's school?
(GRUNTING)
You're like a baby.
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
I need your help.
You should not be here.
-Okay, take me with you.
-No! Go back.
-No.
-(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Go back.
(EXCLAIMING IN NA'VI)
No!
(SPEAKING SHARPLY IN NA'VI)
(REPEATS SOFTLY)
What...
What are they?
Seeds of the Sacred Tree.
Very pure spirits.
Uh-huh.
(CHUCKLES)
What was that all about?
(WHISPERING IN NA'VI)
Come.
Come!
Where are we going?
Come.
What's your name?
Shit!
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(ALL ULULATING)
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Okay.
(YELLS)
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
Calm people, calm.
What are you doing, Tsu'tey?
(SPEAKING IN NA'VI)
These demons are forbidden here.
There has been a sign.
This is a matter for the Tsahik.
Bring him.
What's going on?
(GROANING) Wait.
(ORDERING IN NA'VI)
What's happening?
Hey!
(VILLAGERS CHATTERING)
(HUNTERS WHOOPING)
(NEYTIRI SPEAKING NA'VI)
Father...
...I see you.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
This creature...
...why do you bring him here?
I was going to kill him...
.But there was a sign from Eywa.
I have said...
...no dreamwalker will come here.
What's he saying?
His alien smell fills my nose.
-Hey, what's he saying?
-My father is deciding whether to kill you.
Your father.
It's nice to meet you, sir.
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN NA'VI)
(MO'AT SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
Step back!
I will look at this alien.
That is Mother.
She is Tsahik.
The one who interprets
the will of Eywa.
Who's Eywa?
(IN ENGLISH) What are you called?
Jake Sully.
(GRUNTS)
Why did you come to us?
I came to learn.
We have tried to teach
other Sky People.
It is hard to fill a cup
which is already full.
Well, my cup is
empty, trust me.
Just ask Dr. Augustine.
I'm no scientist.
What are you?
I was a Marine. A...
A warrior of the Jarhead clan.
(TSU'TEY SPEAKING NA'VI)
A warrior!
I could kill him easily!
No!
This is the First warrior dreamwalker...
...WC have 56611.
We need to learn more about him.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
My Daughter...
“you will teach him our way...
...to speak and walk as we do.
Why me? That's not Fair...
-(EXCLAIMS IN ANNOYANCE)
-It is decided.
My daughter will teach you
our ways. Learn well,
Jakesully.
Then we will see if your
insanity can be cured.
(VILLAGERS CHATTERING)
(DRUMS BEATING)
(SINGING IN NA'VI)
(CHATTERING AND SINGING STOP)
(STAMMERING) Good evening.
Please don't get up.
Excuse me.
(EXCLAIMS)
Sorry.
(CHATTERING
AND SINGING RESUME)
Hey, how you doing?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
GRACE: (ECHOING) Jake. Jake!
MAX: He's in alpha.
He's coming out right now.
Jake. Jake.!
GRACE: Come on back, kid.
Come on. That's it.
(GASPING IN CONFUSION)
There you go. There you go, there you go.
You're okay. You're okay.
Damn! You were
dug in like a tick.
(GROANING)
(SIGHS)
-Is the avatar safe?
-Yeah, Doc.
And you are not gonna
believe where I am.
(LAUGHS)
The last thing we see
is this Marine's ass
disappearing into the brush with
this angry thanator coming after him.
-Hey, it's not something you can teach.
-MAX: That is awesome.
You know, for reasons I cannot fathom,
the Omaticaya have chosen you.
God help us all.
(MEN LAUGHING)
-"Jarhead clan"?
-Mmm-hmm.
(LAUGHING) And it worked?
Hey, I'm
practically family.
They're gonna study me.
I have to learn to be one of them.
That's called taking the initiative,
son. I wish I had 10 more like you.
Look, Sully. Sully. Just find out
what the blue monkeys want.
You know, I mean,
we try to give them
medicine, education, roads.
But no, no, no, they like mud.
And that wouldn't bother me,
it's just that they're...
Hey, can you... Can somebody just...
Sector 12.
Okay, go, go, go,
stop. Stop...
Rich, stop!
That's... Jesus!
Their damn village
happens to be resting
on the richest
unobtanium deposit
within 200 klicks in
any direction. I mean,
look at all that cheddar!
(LAUGHS)
Well, who gets them
to move?
Guess.
(SCOFFS)
What if they won't go?
Oh, I'm betting that they will.
Okay, okay, okay,
okay, hey. Look. Look.
Killing the indigenous
looks bad,
but there's one thing
that shareholders hate
more than
bad press,
and that's a bad
quarterly statement.
I didn't make up the rules.
So just find me a carrot
that” get them to move,
otherwise it's gonna have
to be all stick. Okay?
You got three months. That's
when the 'dozers get there.
Well, we're wasting time.
I like this guy.
MAX: Guys, right now...
GRACE: Okay, let's run through them again.
JAKE: Mo'at.
Dragon lady.
-Eytucan.
-Eytukan.
He's the clan leader. But she's
the spiritual leader. Like a shaman.
JAKE: Got it.
-T'su'tey.
-Tsu'tey.
-He'll be the next clan leader.
Neytiri.
She'll be the next Tsahik.
They become a mated pair.
So who's this Eywa?
(SHOCKED) Who's Eywa?
Only their deity.
Their goddess, made up of all
living things. Everything they know!
You'd know this if you had
any training whatsoever.
Who's got a date with
the chief's daughter?
-Come on. That's...
-GRACE: All right, knock it off, you two.
Let's go. Village
life starts early.
Don't do anything
unusually stupid.
JAKE: Easy, boy.
Pale is female.
(NEYTIRI SPEAKING
SOOTHINGLY IN NA'VI)
JAKE: Okay.
Easy, girl.
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING SOOTHINGLY IN NA'VI)
(WHINNYING)
(EXHALING)
That is tsaheylu.
The bond.
Feel her.
Feel her heartbeat.
Her breath.
Feel her strong legs.
You may tell her
what to do.
Inside.
For now,
say where to go.
Forward!
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
You should go away.
No, you'd miss me.
I knew you could speak English.
(SCOFFING)
(SPEAKS NA'VI)
This alien will learn nothing...
...a rock sees more...
...look at him.
(SPEAKS NA'VI)
Again.
JAKE: If you want to hit this thing,
it's gonna be complicated.
Your scan doesn't show
the internal structure.
-There's an outer row of columns.
-QUARITCH: Uh-huh.
Real heavy duty. There's a secondary
ring here, and an inner ring.
There's a core structure like a spiral.
That's how they move up and down.
We're gonna need accurate
scans on every column.
Roger that.
What else can you tell us
about the structure?
JAKE: I'm guessing
this secondary ring,
that's also load-bearing.
So where are we going?
Getting out of Dodge.
I'm not about to let Selfridge and
Quaritch micro-manage this thing.
There's a mobile link up at Site 26 we can
work out of, way up in the mountains.
The Hallelujah Mountains?
-That's right.
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
-Yes!
(NORM LAUGHING)
The legendary floating mountains
of Pandora. Heard of them?
We're getting close.
Yeah, look at
my instruments.
Yep. We're in
the Flux Vortex.
We're VFR
from here on.
What's VFR?
Means you gotta see
Where you're going.
You can't see anything.
(LAUGHING) Exactly. Ain't that a bitch?
Oh, my God.
(LAUGHING) You should see your faces.
Thank you for flying Air Pandora.
(AIRLOCK HISSING)
Welcome to camp.
GRACE: So,
this is my bunk.
This stuff is nasty.
GRACE: Norm, go under.
NORM: All right.
JAKE: Grace didn't miss a thing.
GRACE: Trudy, you'll take the top one.
She knew I was talking
to the Colonel.
But I had what she needed,
a way back in with the clan,
so she's playing nice.
All right. Jake, hang a left.
You'll be in the
link at the end.
Unit one.
Beulah. She's
the least glitchy.
(IMITATING BIRD CALL)
(BIRDS CAWING)
(SQUAWKING)
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY) Holy shit!
Do not look in her eye.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Ikran is not horse.
Once tsaheylu is made,
ikran will fly with only one
hunter in the whole life.
To become taronyu, hunter,
you must choose your own ikran
and he must choose you.
-When?
-When you are ready.
(EXCLAIMS)
(NEYTIRI WHOOPING)
Okay.
This is video log 12.
Time's 2132.
(SIGHING) Do I have to do this now?
I really need to get some rack.
No, now.
When it's fresh.
Okay, location, shack,
and the days are starting
to blur together.
(SPEAKING NA'VI SLOWLY)
(REPEATING TENTATIVELY)
JAKE: The language is
a pain, but, you know,
I figure it's like field-stripping a weapon.
Just repetition, repetition.
-Navi.
-"Nari."!
-Nari.
-(IMPATIENTLY) "Narrri”!
Narrri!
Txur ni'ul. Stronger.
(INHALES)
JAKE: Neytiri calls me skxawng.
It means moron.
This is a very
important part of it.
Norm's attitude
has improved lately.
-I see you. I see you.
-But it's not just,
"I'm seeing you in front of me,"
it's "I see into you. I See you."
It's good he's back on board,
but he thinks I'm a skxawng, too.
"I'm accepting you. I understand you."
So you gotta get this, okay?
I gotta run! Okay? Let's go.
My feet are
getting tougher.
I can run farther
every day.
I have to trust my body
to know what to do.
Yeah! Check it out!
Oh, crap!
Every day it's reading the trails,
the tracks at the waterhole,
the tiniest scents and sounds.
(CUBS SQUEAKING)
She's always going on
about the flow of energy,
the spirits of animals.
I really hope this tree-hugger
crap isn't on the final.
This isn't just about eye-hand
coordination out there, you know.
You need to listen to what she says.
Try to see the forest through her eyes.
Excuse me.
This is my video log here.
With Neytiri, it's
learn fast or die.
You gotta be kidding me.
(SCREAMING)
-(BRANCHES CRACKING)
-(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
I talked Mo'at into letting
Grace into the village.
Look how big you are-.
It's the first time since
her school was closed down.
You are so Pretty.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa. No, you don't.
Come back here.
Bon appétit.
(CHIRPING)
(POWERING OFF)
(GENTLY) Come on, Marine.
JAKE: I'm trying to understand this deep
connection the people have to the forest.
She talks about a network of energy
that flows through all living things.
She says all energy
is only borrowed,
and one day you have to give it back.
(GROWLS)
(MOANING)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
1566 you...
.-.Brother
...and thank you.
Your spirit goes with Eywa.
Your body stays behind...
...to become Part of The People.
A clean kill.
You are ready.
JAKE: Learning to ride an ikran,
we call them banshees, is the test
every young hunter has to pass.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
But to do that, you gotta go
where the banshees are.
Oo-rah.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Now what?
(COMMANDS IN NA'VI)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(HUNTER WHOOPING)
(SCREECHING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(NEYTIRI SPEAKING NA'VI)
(SPEAKING SOFTLY IN NA'VI)
(PANTING)
Jakesully will go first.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(SCREECHING)
Now you choose
your ikran.
This you must feel inside.
If he also chooses you,
move quick like I showed.
You will have one chance, Jake.
How will I know
if he chooses me?
He will try to kill you.
Outstanding.
(EXCLAIMS)
(HISSING)
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMING)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
(ROARING)
(SPEAKS NA'VI)
(HISSING)
Let's dance.
(LAUGHING)
That moron's going to die.
(SCREECHING)
(WHOOPING)
(GRUNTING)
Don't be afraid, warrior.
Make the bond!
(GRUNTING) No!
(EXCLAIMS)
Jake!
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(IKRAN SCREECHING)
(SHOUTING)
Tsaheylu, Jake.
NEYTIRI: Tsaheylu!
(YELLING)
Stop!
(SPEAKING SOFTLY IN NA'VI)
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, that's right.
You're mine. Huh?
First flight seals the bond.
You cannot wait.
Think, "Fly!"
Fly?
(EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMING)
God damn!
Oh, shit!
(YELLING)
(SCREECHING)
Shut up and fly straight!
(JAKE PANTING)
That's it.
Bank left!
Level out!
That's it.
(HUNTERS WHOOPING)
WARRIOR: Whoo! Jakesully!
(WHOOPING)
(SPEAKS SHARPLY
IN NA'VI)
(CHUCKLING)
(NEYTIRI HOOTING)
Hey!
Let's go!
Yeah, baby, I got this!
Oh, shit!
(WHOOPING)
JAKE: I may not be much of a horse
guy, but I was born to do this.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah!
-I came like this. This you.
-Yeah, yeah.
I turn. I feel the wind.
I turn very strong.
Look, yeah, see, I banked so hard...
(GASPS)
(SPEAKS NA'VI)
(LAUGHING)
(JAKE WHOOPING)
GRACE: The Tree of Souls.
(TRANSLATING INTO NA'VI)
It's their most sacred place.
See the Flux Vortex in
these false color images?
Yeah, that's what
messes up my instruments.
There is something really interesting
going on in there biologically.
I would die
to get samples.
Outsiders are
strictly forbidden.
GRACE: You lucky swine.
JAKE: I was a stone-cold aerial hunter.
Death from above.
Only problem is,
you're not the only one.
(JAKE AND NEYTIRI
EXCHANGING YELPS)
Dive!
(ROARING)
(SCREECHING)
Go, go!
(NEYTIRI IMITATING BIRD CRIES)
Follow me!
(ROARING)
(SOFTLY) Whew.
(BOTH HOOTING)
(SPEAKING SOOTHINGLY IN NA'VI)
(SHUSHING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Our guys call it a
Great Leonopteryx.
It is Toruk.
Last Shadow.
Yeah, right.
It's the last one you ever see.
My grandfather's grandfather
was Toruk Macto.
Rider of Last Shadow.
He rode this?
Toruk chose him.
It has only happened five times
since the time of the First Songs.
-That's a long time.
-Yes.
Toruk Macto was mighty.
He brought the clans together
in a time of great sorrow.
All Na'vi people
know the story.
(INHALING DEEPLY)
JAKE: Everything is backwards now.
Like out there is
the true world
and in here is the dream.
(SIGHS)
It's hard to believe it's
only been three months.
I can barely remember
my old life.
I don't know who I am anymore.
(SNIFFLES)
Haven't gotten lost in
the woods, have you?
Your last report was
more than two weeks ago.
I'm starting to doubt
your resolve!
The way I see it, it's time
to terminate the mission.
No, I can do this.
You already have.
You give me good, usable intel.
This Tree of Souls place.
Yeah, I got them by the balls with that
when this turns into a shit fight,
which it will.
Yeah.
Now it's time
to come in.
By the way,
you gonna get your legs back.
Yeah. I got your corporate
approval. It's a done deal.
Gonna have you
on a shuttle tonight.
I'm a man of my word.
I gotta finish this.
There's one more thing.
Ceremony. It's the final stage
of becoming a man.
If I do it, I'm one of them.
And they'll trust me.
And I can negotiate the
terms of their relocation.
Well, then, you'd better
get it done, Corporal.
JAKE: The Na'vi say that every
person is born twice.
The second time
is when you earn your place
among The People
forever.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
You are now a son of the Omaticaya.
You are Part of The People.
(SNIFFLING SOFTLY)
(LAUGHING)
Come.
(LAUGHS)
This is a place for
prayers to be heard.
And sometimes answered.
(SIGHS)
We call these trees
Utra ya Mokri.
The Tree of Voices.
The voices of our ancestors.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(VOICES CHATTERING DISTANTLY)
I can hear them.
They live, Jake,
within Eywa.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
You are Omaticaya now.
You may make your bow
from the wood of Hometree.
And you may choose a woman.
We have many fine women.
Ninat is the best singer.
But I don't want Ninat.
(BLOWING)
Peyral is a good hunter.
Yeah, she is a good hunter.
(EXHALES)
(SOFTLY) I've already chosen.
But this woman
must also choose me.
She already has.
(GASPS)
I am with you now, Jake.
We are mated for life.
JAKE: What the hell are you doing, Jake?
(MACHINERY RUMBLING)
(BRANCH CRACKING)
(MACHINERY APPROACHING)
(GASPING)
(ENGINES RUMBLING)
Ma Jake!
NORM: Don't forget your
phase integration.
-GRACE: Jake!
-No, no, the middle button.
-You gotta eat something.
-Yeah, there you go.
Jake. Jake.
Wake up! Jake, please!
Don't make me
force-feed a cripple.
(CHUCKLES) Grace, I don't want... Hey!
(POWERING DOWN)
(GRUNTS IN ALARM)
Jake!
(CHUCKLING) Okay.
(GRUNTING)
Here. I'm done. Let's go.
And when was the last time
you took a shower?
-I don't need a shower.
-Jesus, Marine.
(GRUNTING)
Jake!
Jake! Wake up!
Hey!
Stop! Stop!
-NEYTIRI: Jake!
-Go back, stop!
Hey, boss.
Hey!
(BULLDOZER POWERING DOWN)
What?
I got a native doing
the funky chicken here.
He's blocking my blade.
Well, keep going.
He'll move.
SELFRIDGE: These people have to learn
that we don't stop. Come on, go, go, go.
Stop! Hey!
Go! Go!
There, see? He moved.
(GRUNTING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Dude, dude. Whoa,
dude! Dude, no!
Oh! I'm blind.
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
—Jake!
—Neytiri!
Here, come on!
(NEYTIRI SOBBING)
(INHALING)
QUARITCH: Freeze it right there.
Scale up. Enhance.
SELFRIDGE: Son of a bitch.
Unbelievable.
-Get me a pilot.
-Yes, sir.
(HUNTERS HOOTING WAR CRIES)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Tsu'tey will lead the war Party.
(ALL SHOUTING WAR CRIES)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Stop Please!
This will only make it worse.
You do not speak here!
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
We will strike them in the heart.
(ALL SHOUTING WAR CRIES)
JAKE: Tsu'tey!
Don't do this.
You!
-Listen. Brother...
-(SHOUTS IN NA'VI)
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
You mated
with this woman?
Oh, shit.
(STERNLY) Is this true?
We are mated before Eywa.
It is done.
(BREATHING TREMULOUSLY)
JAKE: Brother, please.
Do not attack the Sky People.
Many Omaticaya
-will die if you do.
-You are not my brother!
(YELLING)
And I am not your enemy!
The enemy is out there,
and they are very powerful!
Go! Go! Go!
-I can talk to them.
-No more talk.
NEYTIRI: Tsu'tey!
I am Omaticaya.
I am one of you.
And I have the right to speak.
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
I have something to sag...
...to a” of you.
(IN ENGLISH) The words are like
stones in my heart.
NORM: Sir, I'm sorry. No, no, no! Hold on!
You can't interrupt a link in progress!
It's very dangerous!
NEYTIRI: Grace!
Oh, no.
-Wait!
-Stay down, sir.
(BEEPING)
Okay. Look...
I was sent here to...
(CROWD MURMURING)
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
You see?
It is a demon in a False body.
(NEYTIRI YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GASPS)
Are you out of
your goddamn mind?
You crossed the line.
Wheel this meat
out of here.
GRACE: Jake! What the hell
is going on here?
QUARITCH: You let me down, son.
So, what,
you find yourself
some local tail
and you just completely forget
what team you're playing for?
Parker, there is time
to salvage the situation.
-Parker...
-Shut your pie hole!
Or what, Ranger Rick?
You gonna shoot me?
I could do that.
You need to
muzzle your dog.
Yeah, can we just take this down
a couple of notches, please?
You say you want to
keep your people alive?
You start by
listening to her.
Those trees were sacred to the Omaticaya
in a way you can't imagine.
You know what? You throw
a stick in the air around here,
it's gonna land on some sacred fern,
(MOCKINGLY) for Christ's sake!
I'm not talking about some
kind of pagan voodoo here.
I'm talking about something real,
something measurable in
the biology of the forest.
Which is what, exactly?
What we think
we know
is that there is some kind of
electrochemical communication
between the roots of the trees,
like the synapses between neurons.
And each tree has
ten-to-the-fourth connections
to the trees around it. And there are
ten-to-the-twelfth trees on Pandora.
Which is a lot, I'm guessing.
It's more connections
than the human brain.
Get it? It's
a network.
It's a global network,
and the Na'vi can access it.
They can upload and
download data. Memories.
At sites like the one
you just destroyed.
(IN AWE) Yes!
(LAUGHING) What the hell have you
people been smoking out there?
They're just goddamn trees!
(LAUGHING)
-You need to wake up, Parker.
-No. You need to wake up.
The wealth of this world isn't
in the ground. It's all around us.
The Na'vi know that, and
they are fighting to defend it.
If you want to share this world with
them, you need to understand them.
I'd say we understand them
just fine, thanks to Jake here.
Hey, Doc,
come take a look.
They're not gonna
give up their home.
They're not gonna make a deal.
(SCOFFING) For what? Lite beer?
And blue jeans?
There's nothing that
we have that they want.
Everything they sent me out here
to do is a waste of time.
They're never gonna
leave Hometree.
So,
since a deal can't be made,
I guess things get real simple.
Jake, thanks.
I'm getting all emotional.
I might just give you a big wet kiss.
(SIGHS)
I'll do it with minimal casualties
to the indigenous.
I'll drive them out with gas first.
(SIGHS)
It'll be humane.
More or less.
All right, let's
pull the trigger.
-MAX: Come on, people.
-(SIGHING) Oh, man.
MAX: Let's pack it
up, let's go.
This is how it's done.
When people are sitting
on shit that you want,
you make them your enemy.
Then you're justified
in taking it.
Quaritch is rolling the gunships.
He's gonna hit Hometree.
My God.
Dr. Augustine! You
cannot be up here!
Back off! Parker.
Wait. Stop. These are
people you're about to...
-No. No, no, no, no.
-I said back off!
They're fly-bitten savages that live
in a tree! All right? Look around!
I don't know about you, but I see
a lot of trees! They can move!
-Can you guys just please...
-Yes, sir.
There are families in there.
There are children. Babies.
Are you gonna kill children?
You don't want that kind of blood
on your hands. Believe me.
Just let me try
to talk them out.
They trust me.
Calibrate fast. We're
going in, right now.
FEMALE TECHNICIAN:
Calibrating three and four.
GRACE: Run sequence.
MAX: Initiating. Thirty seconds.
(POWERING UP)
Listen to me. You've got one hour.
Unless you want your girlfriend
in there when the ax comes down,
you get them to evacuate.
One hour.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Father!
Mother!
Eytukan, I have something to say.
Listen!
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Speak, Jakesully..
A great av“ is upon us...
The Sky People are coming...
...to destroy Hometree.
Look, tell them they're
gonna be here soon.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
(IN ENGLISH) You have to
leave, or you're gonna die.
Are you certain of this?
Look, they sent me here
to learn your ways
so one day I could bring this message
and that you would believe it.
What are you saying, Jake?
You knew this would happen?
Yes.
Look, at first it
was just orders,
and then everything changed.
Okay? I fell in love.
I fell in love
with the forest
and with the Omaticaya people.
And with you.
I trusted you.
-With you. With you.
-I trusted you!
Trust me now, please.
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
You will never be one of The People!
-I shouldn't have...
-We tried to stop them!
Neytiri, please! Please.
(MO'AT SPEAKING NA'VI)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Bind them.
(GRACE SPEAKING NA'VI)
Leave now!
You have to go.
They're coming!
(SHOUTING WAR CRY)
(ALL SHOUTING WAR CRY)
DRAGON PILOT: Time on target, one mike.
SCORPION PILOT: Copy. We have a visual.
Roger that. Stay
on heading 030.
SCORPION PILOT: Roger, 030.
(BOTH SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
-Run to the forest!
-They're coming!
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
They will destroy this place.
Neytiri, you must go now!
(YIPPING)
Run to the forest! Run!
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
Run! Run!
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Have no Fear.
No! God damn it, run!
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Take the ikran...
...attack< From above.
(SPEAKS NA'VI)
That is one
big damn tree.
Well, well, well.
I'd say diplomacy
has failed.
All right, people,
let's get this done!
I want every gas round you
got right in the front door.
Roger. CS .40's going hot.
-Fire.
-Firing.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL COUGHING)
Bingo. Mighty good shooting, ace.
(SCREAMING IN NA'VI)
Sir, they've
opened fire.
(ARROWS CLATTERING)
You've got to be kidding me!
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
(ALL COUGHING)
These dumb bastards
ain't getting the message.
All right, let's turn up the
heat. Switch incendiaries!
Switching incendiaries.
Fire.
No!
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
(EYTUKAN SPEAKS NA'VI)
Get everyone to the Forest.
And that's how you
scatter the roaches.
(EYTUKAN SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
JAKE: Neytiri!
We gotta move!
He's gonna blow the columns!
My God!
(COMMANDING IN NA'VI)
(PROTESTING)
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
Mo'at! No!
If you are one of us,
help us.
All call signs,
switch missiles.
Give me HE's at the base
of the west columns.
This way!
OFFICER ON RADIO:
Rider section, switch missiles.
PILOT 1: One's good.
PILOT 2: Two's rocks up.
PILOT 3: Three's up.
Yeah, baby, get some!
Charlie Oscar, Gunrunner standing by.
Bring it down.
Cleared hot.
(ALL GRUNTING)
Come on, Grace, move!
Down!
Head down!
Come on, come on!
Down!
(GROANING)
PILOT 1: Solid hits.
PILOT 2: Solid rocks on target.
Screw this.
Hey! What the hell
are you doing?
I didn't sign up
for this shit!
OFFICER: Repeat.
Ripple fire.
(WOOD CREAKING)
Go! Go! Go!
(VILLAGERS SCREAMING)
(YIPPING)
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
(SCREECHING)
No, no, get back! Back!
(YELLS)
(EXCLAIMING IN PANIC)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Come on! Come on,
move! Move!
(VILLAGERS SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING IN HORROR)
That's good work, people.
First round's on me tonight.
Let's boogie.
PILOT: Dragon coming left,
heading home.
OFFICER: Gunrunner coming left.
-Thunder copies.
-Rider section copies.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Father!
(MOANING)
(WAILING IN NA'VI)
(GROANING WEAKLY)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Daughter...
take.. mg.. bow.
(SOBBING)
Protect The People.
Neytiri!
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
(WAILING IN GRIEF)
I'm sorry.
(SOBBING) Get away.
(SHRIEKING) Get away!
Get away from here!
Never come back!
(WAILING)
Pull the plug.
-No, you can't do that!
-WOMAN: You can't do that!
-Calm down! Calm down!
-No! Please!
(GIRL SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
JAKE: I was a warrior who dreamed
he could bring peace.
(ALL ARGUING)
Sooner or later, though,
you always have to wake up.
(DISTANTLY) Let's go!
Put him down!
You murderer!
(VILLAGERS SOBBING)
What's going on, brother?
Long time no see.
SECURITY MAN: Hey.
Personally, I don't feel these
tree-hugging traitors deserve steak.
They get steak? That's
bullshit. Let me see that.
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah. You know
What that is. Down.
Trudy!
All the way down.
(GROANS)
Max!
Trudy, fire up
the ship! Go!
Here.
Clear. Come on.
Here you go.
Max, stay here.
I need someone
on the inside I can trust.
Okay. Go.
NORM: (SOFTLY) Clear.
(ENGINE POWERING UP)
Come on, baby.
Colonel? Sir? I got
a situation here.
It's Samson 1-6.
Unauthorized engine start.
NORM: (GRUNTING) Three!
Come on!
Mask on!
Gas, gas, gas!
I'm taking fire!
Let's go!
Grab my hand!
Come on, we're
in. Let's go!
Come on, let's go!
Let's go, go!
Colonel!
(AIR HISSING)
Yeah! Yeah!
NORM: All right! Yes!
(LAUGHS)
(WHOOPING)
Crap.
TRUDY: Everybody all right back there?
JAKE: Oh, yeah, baby!
-Norm, you good?
-NORM: Yeah!
(GROANING) This is gonna ruin
my whole day.
Grace is hit!
What?
-Get the trauma kit.
-Trauma kit!
Keep the pressure on, Grace.
Trauma kit's forward,
on the bulkhead.
Hang on, Grace.
Doesn't matter.
It's fine.
(STIFLES GROAN)
JAKE ON RADIO: You're good to go.
Take it up!
TRUDY ON RADIO: Hold on.
I'm pulling pitch.
You're clear!
Just keep going north.
Get us deep in the mountains.
TRUDY: Copy that.
Norm, you all good up there?
Yep! Still here.
Well, at least they can't track us
up here. Not this far into the Vortex.
It's strongest at the
Tree of Souls, right?
Yeah.
Good. 'Cause that's
where we're going.
Ouch.
You big baby.
We're moving.
I'm gonna get you some help, Grace.
I'm a scientist, remember?
I don't believe in fairy tales.
The People can
help you. I know it.
Why would they help us?
JAKE: The People say
Eywa will provide.
With no home,
no hope,
there was only one place they could go.
(SOBBING)
Link's
running.
-What's the plan here, Jake?
-There's no plan.
Tsu'tey is Olo'eyktan now.
He's not gonna let you near that place.
I gotta try.
Launching.
(EXHALES)
(COUGHING)
JAKE: Outcast.
Betrayer.
Alien.
I was in the place
the eye does not see.
I needed their help,
and they needed mine.
But to ever face
them again,
I was gonna have to take it
to a whole new level.
(SCREECHING)
Sometimes your whole life
boils down to one insane move.
There's something we gotta do.
You're not gonna like it.
Yam!
(SQUAWKING)
The way I had it figured, Toruk
is the baddest cat in the sky.
Nothing attacks him.
Easy, boy.
So why would he
ever look up?
But that was just a theory.
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(ALL SINGING IN NA'VI)
(ALL MURMURING
IN GROWING ALARM)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
Toruk Macto?
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
(VILLAGERS MURMURING)
(PANTING SOFTLY)
I See you.
I was afraid, Jake.
For my people.
I'm not anymore.
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
Tsu'tcg, son of Atcgo...
...I stand before you...
“ready to serve
the Omaticaya People.
(IN ENGLISH) You are Olo'eyktan,
and you are a great warrior.
I can't do this without you.
(ROARING)
Toruk Macto,
I will fly with you.
My friend is dying.
Grace is dying.
I beg the help of Eywa.
(ALL CHANTING)
Look where we are, Grace.
I need to take some samples.
(JAKE CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
The Great Mother may choose
to save all that she is
in this body.
Is that possible?
She must pass through
the eye of Eywa and return.
But, Jakesully,
she is very weak.
Hang on, Grace.
They're gonna fix you up.
(MO'AT SPEAKING NA'VI)
Hear us Please, A” Mother.
Eywa, help her.
Take this spirit into you...
(ALL REPLYING IN NA'VI)
...and breathe her back to us.
Let her wall< among us...
(ALL REPLYING IN NA'VI)
...as one of The People.
(ALL CHANTING)
(SPEAKS NA'VI)
(CHANTING STOPS)
(WEAKLY) Jake.
Grace.
I'm with her, Jake.
She's real!
(DISTANTLY) Grace? Grace, please. Grace!
What's happening?
Grace!
JAKE: What's happening?
Did it work?
Her wounds were too great.
It was not enough time.
She is with Eywa now.
With your permission,
I will speak now.
You would honor
me by translating.
The Sky People have
sent us a message
(TSU'TEY TRANSLATING)
That they can take
whatever they want
and no one can stop them.
Well, we will send
them a message.
You ride out as fast as
the wind can carry you.
You tell the other
clans to come.
(EXCLAIMING IN AGREEMENT)
You tell them Toruk Macto calls to them.
And you fly now with me!
My brothers!
Sisters!
(ALL HOOTING)
And we will show
the Sky People
that they cannot take
whatever they want,
and that this,
this is our land!
(REPEATING IN NA'VI)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ROARS) Yam!
(EXCLAIMING IN NA'VI)
Yam!
(SCREECHING)
(ALL CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
(HOOTING)
Yam!
JAKE: We rode out
to the four winds.
(SHOUTS IN NA'VI)
To the horse clans of the plain.
JAKE: Back to the stars!
To the Man people
of the Eastern Sea.
For our children's children!
When Toruk Macks
called them, they came.
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
(ALL CHEERING)
Yam!
(ULULATING)
(NEYTIRI HOOTING)
Everyone on this base,
every one of you,
is fighting for survival.
That's a fact!
There's an aboriginal horde
out there massing for an attack.
Now, these orbital
images tell me
that the hostiles' numbers
have gone from a few hundred
to well over 2,000 in one day.
And more are pouring in.
In a week's time, there
could be 20,000 of them.
At that point, they will overrun our
perimeter. Well, that's not gonna happen!
Our only security lies
in pre-emptive attack.
We will fight terror
with terror.
Now, the hostiles believe
that this mountain
stronghold of theirs
is protected by their...
(SCORNFULLY) Their deity.
(SOLDIERS SNICKERING)
And when we destroy it,
we will blast a crater in
their racial memory so deep
that they won't come within
1,000 klinks of this place ever again.
And that, too, is a fact.
(SOLDIERS CHEERING)
Yeah! Yeah.
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING)
Jake, it's crazy here. It's full mobilization.
They're rigging the shuttle as a bomber.
They've got these huge
pallets of mine explosives.
It's for some kind of
shock-and-awe campaign.
Fricking daisy cutters!
Quaritch has taken over.
He's rolling, and there's
no stopping him.
-When?
-0600 tomorrow.
-WOMAN: Max! Max!
-I gotta go.
We're screwed!
(TRUDY LAUGHING)
And I was hoping for some sort of tactical
plan that didn't involve martyrdom.
TRUDY: We're going up against gunships
with bows and arrows.
I have 15 clans out there.
That's over 2,000 warriors.
Now, we know these
mountains. We fly them.
You fly them. They don't.
Their instruments won't work up here.
Missile tracking won't work.
They'll have to fire a line of sight.
If they bring the fight to us, then
we have the home-field advantage.
You know he's gonna commit that
bomber straight to the Tree of Souls.
Yeah, I know.
If they get to the Tree of Souls, it's over.
That's their direct line to Eywa,
their ancestors. It'll destroy them.
Then I guess
we'd better stop him.
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
I'm probably just talking
to a tree right now.
(SIGHS)
But if you're there,
I need to give you a heads-up.
If Grace is with you,
look into her memories.
See the world we come from.
There's no green there.
They killed their Mother.
And they're gonna do the same here.
More Sky People are gonna come.
They're gonna come
like a rain that never ends.
Unless we stop them.
Look, you chose me
for something.
I will stand and fight.
You know I will.
But I need a little help here.
Our Great Mother
does not take sides, Jake.
(SIGHS)
She protects only
the balance of life.
It was worth a try.
(BOTH SIGHING)
MAN: Yeah! Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about!
Yeah! Yeah! That's what
I'm talking about, man!
This is Group Leader. We
are entering the Flux Vortex.
-Switch to manual flight mode.
-PILOT: Copy. Manual flight mode.
This is Papa Dragon.
I want this mission high and tight.
I want to be home for dinner.
Suit Team, go.
All right, ladies,
let's bring the pain!
STAFF SERGEANT: Move, move, move!
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 1:
Bravo 1-1, move left.
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 2:
Bravo 1-1 moving left. Watch flank.
-Watch formation. Keep moving.
-AMPSUIT COMMANDER 1: Roger that.
Charlie 2-1,
watch your spacing.
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 1: Copy that. Over.
Eyes up. Check
that overhead.
And watch those
thermal scans.
All call signs, Papa has
lead, pushing to target.
Escorts, stay close
on my shuttle.
We are gonna lose some paint in here.
QUARITCH: Gun crews, keep your head on a
swivel. Make no mistake, people,
they're out there.
All right, people, target
in sight. Range, four klicks.
Valkyrie 1-6, get
your payload ready.
Copy. Prepare
to offload.
Staff Sergeant,
stage the weapon.
Roll it to the ramp!
Let's go!
Hold!
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 2:
Charlie 2-1, got big movement.
-Hold position.
-Hold up, hold up.
-We got movement out there, 500 meters.
-Charlie 2-1, hold position.
Sir, ground has movement!
Fast approaching.
PILOT: Charlie Oscar, Rider section.
Firing line!
Targets closing.
Range, 400 meters.
Can't you clean it up?
No, sir. It's the Flux.
(SHOUTING)
(WHOOPING)
(WARRIORS HOOTING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
(HOOTING)
(SHOUTING IN NA'VI)
(ULULATING)
(WHOOPING)
Brother, I'm gonna punch a hole.
You follow me through.
(RESPONDS IN NA'VI)
(ALL ULULATING)
(APPROACHING WAR CRIES)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
All aircraft, weapons
free! Weapons free!
Break right.
Come around.
Light them up!
Break formation,
engage all hostiles.
Yeah! Get some!
(SCREAMING)
Scorpions, pursue and destroy.
Jake. Jake.
You copy?
We're falling back!
We're getting hammered!
Copy. Get out of there.
(SCREECHING)
That's him. Get after him!
Take him out!
Oops.
Light her up!
Right there!
You're not the only one
with a gun, bitch.
-Keep her in your sights.
-Purging. Feeding the leak.
Arming all pods.
That's it!
(GASPS)
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTING)
Seze!
(GASPING IN CONCERN)
(SHRIEKS)
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTING)
TRUDY: Rogue One is hit.
I'm going in.
Sorry, Jake.
(GRUNTS)
Fire.
(PANTING)
Tsu'tey!
Brother, do you read?
Rogue One,
you copy?
Trudy!
(GASPING)
Time to target, two minutes.
Valkyrie 1-6, you are
cleared and hot.
Copy, Dragon. We are
starting our bomb run.
Arm number one!
Number one armed!
Ma Jake!
I read you.
JAKE: Neytiri!
Seze's dead.
They are very close. They are many.
Do not attack.
Do you read me, Neytiri?
Do not attack!
Fall back now.
Get out of there!
That's an order!
Neytiri!
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 2:
I got movement, I got movement.
Hold position.
Something's coming.
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 1: Bravo 1-1,
I got a big seating. Turn screens over.
-We got movement 200 meters.
-Hold your formation.
-Be ready.
-Watch your flanks.
Hundred meters and closing fast.
(TRUMPETING)
(EXCLAIMING)
We gotta get out of here!
Fall back! Fall back!
AMPSUIT COMMANDER 1:
Move! Move! Move!
Fall back! On the run!
On the run!
(SCREAMING)
Jake, Eywa has heard you.
(SCREECHING)
Eywa has heard you!
(ALL SCREECHING)
Come on!
(SNARLING)
Fall back! Move! Move!
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(ROARING)
(ROARS)
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
PILOT: Sir! All escorts are
down or falling back.
Let's get this done.
Valkyrie 1-6,
this is Dragon.
Press to target.
Copy. Pressing
to target.
Stand by to drop,
30 seconds.
(SHOUTING)
On my mark.
Two, one, mark.
Drop! Drop! Drop!
Go, go, go, go!
(SCREAMING)
QUARITCH: Brace!
QUARITCH: It's Sully.
(ALARM BLARING)
-Mask on!
-Breach alarm!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Come on.
Come to papa.
(NEYTIRI SCREAMING)
(HOWLING IN PAIN)
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTING)
(NEYTIRI GROANING)
(HISSING)
JAKE: Give it up, Quaritch!
It's all over.
Nothing's over
while I'm breathing.
I kind of hoped
you'd say that.
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
Come on!
(GASPS)
Hey, Sully,
how's it feel to
betray your own race?
(HISSING)
You think you're one of them?
Time to wake up.
(ALARM BLARING)
(JAKE GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(COUGHING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(GASPING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTS)
(HISSING)
Jake?
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Jake.
(PANTING SHALLOWLY)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(MOANING)
Jake!
Ma Jake!
(AIR HISSING FAINTLY)
(COUGHING)
(PRESSURIZING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
I See you.
JAKE: The aliens went back
to their dying world.
Only a few
were chosen to stay.
The time of great
sorrow was ending.
Toruk Macto was
no longer needed.
(SCREECHING)
Well, I guess this is
my last video log.
'Cause whatever
happens tonight,
either way, I'm...
I'm not gonna be coming
back to this place.
Well, I guess
I'd better go.
Yeah, I don't want to be
late for my own party.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, it's my
birthday, after all.
This is Jake Sully signing off.
(ALL CHANTING)
(SPEAKING NA'VI)
(I SEE YOU PLAYING)
Walking through a dream
I see you
My light in darkness
breathing hope of new life
Now I live through you
and you through me
Enchanting
I pray in my heart
That this dream never ends
I see me through your eyes
Breathing new life,
flying high
Your love shines the way
into paradise
So I offer my life
I offer my love for you
And my heart was never open
And my spirit never free
To the world
that you have shown me
But my eyes
could not envision
All the colors of love
and of life evermore
Evermore
I see me through your eyes
Flying high
Your love shines the way
into paradise
So I offer my life
as a sacrifice
I live through your love
I live
Through your life
I see you
English - US - SDH